A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, M-R FA393
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Marshall, John
  - 1938 January 4-December 29, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 251 pages (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 356, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall travels to Europe to explore library activities and survey film and radio projects as well as surveys the relations of World Wide Broadcasting Foundation, Harvard University and Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
    Diaries; Radio; Sweden; Switzerland; United States; Drama; Denmark; Broadcasting; Finland; Film; England; Educational films; Libraries; Motion pictures; France; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Norway
  - 1939 January 3-June 26, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 163 pages (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 607, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents the progress on various film and radio projects.
    Broadcasting; Film; Humanities; Diaries; United States; Radio; Motion pictures
  - 1939 July 5-December 27, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 99 pages (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 770, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents the progress on various film and radio projects. He also attends an informal conference on Motion Pictures in Latin America.
    United States; Television; Radio; Motion pictures; Latin America; Diaries; Humanities; Film; Broadcasting
  - 1940 January 2-June 26, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 179 pages (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 871, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication.
    Humanities; Film; Broadcasting; Diaries; United States; Motion pictures; Radio; National Broadcasting Company
  - 1940 July 8-December 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 181 pages (Reel M Mar 3, Frame 1, Box 293)
    Diaries; Radio; United States; Film; Broadcasting
  - 1941 January 6-June 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 293 pages (Box 293, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 182)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication. Marshall attends various conferences on communication research, available multilingual personnel and intelligence services.
    Motion pictures; Radio; Film; Language and languages; Broadcasting; Diaries
  - 1941 July 1-December 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 211 pages (Reel M Mar 3, Frame 475, Box 293)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication. The various interviews include humanities program updates, fellowship progress and determination of grant applications.
    Broadcasting; Humanities; Canada; Motion pictures; Film; Radio; Diaries; United States
  - 1942 January 2-June 24, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 168 pages (Reel M Mar 3, Frame 686, Box 293)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to foreign language studies in support of the war effort, regional studies of North America and continued support to drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Cornell University to survey the English department, discuss plans for a summer workshop and studies on New York State regionalism. The New School for Social Research's project on Totalitarian Communication in Wartime is documented as well.
    Broadcasting; Diaries; Libraries; Motion pictures; Education; Humanities; Radio; United States
  - 1942 July 1-December 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 136 pages (Reel M Mar 3, Frame 854, Box 293)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to foreign language studies in support of the war effort, regional studies of North America and continued support to drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He surveys various universities in North America, locates talent for regionalism prong of Rockefeller Foundation Humanities program and discusses library assistance.
    Libraries; Humanities; Education; Drama; United States; Radio; Diaries; Canada
  - 1943 January 1-June 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 248 pages (Box 294, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 990)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The division focuses on studies in foreign languages, American studies, drama, film and radio. Marshall documents current and future projects. He surveys programs in language and culture of Latin America and East Asia, and Slavic studies. Rehabilitation of European libraries after the war is discussed. He visits Vermont as part of the Rockefeller Foundation's American regionalism program and attends various conferences and workshops.
    United States; Vermont; Canada; Humanities; Film; Education; Drama; Radio; Diaries; Motion pictures; Microfilms; Libraries
  - 1943 July 1-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 186 pages (Box 294, Reel M Mar 4, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The division focuses on studies in foreign languages, American studies, drama, film and radio. Marshall documents current and future projects. The development of Cornell University's Slavic studies program is detailed as well as rehabilitation programs for libraries abroad. He attends the Conference on the Humanities in American Institutions and travels to Quebec and Cleveland, Ohio.
    Diaries; Broadcasting; Canada; Education; Humanities; Libraries; Motion pictures; Radio; Russia -- Study and teaching; Slavic studies; United States
  - 1944 January 3-May 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 213 pages (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 187, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. Grants were primarily given for the study and reorganization of academic disciplines, studies in American and Far East culture and language, drama radio and film. Marshall documents current and future projects. Organization of library centers in China, Mexico and South America is detailed as well as a discussion with the Library of Congress for library rehabilitation in London. Provisions for restoration of objects of art in war areas are documented as well as a Commission on the Function of Philosophy in Liberal Education.
    Humanities; Film; Motion pictures; Language and languages; Radio; Philosophy and religion; United States; Slavic studies; Diaries; Drama; Education
  - 1944 June 1-December 21, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 400, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The contents include meetings about various cultural relations programs. Discussions with the Joint Committee of National Library Associations, ACLS Committee on the Protection of Cultural Objects in War Areas and the American Library Association Committee are detailed regarding aid to libraries in war areas and book campaigns for European libraries.
    Broadcasting; Diaries; Drama; England; Education; Radio; United States; Libraries; Motion pictures; History; Humanities; Europe; Film
  - 1945 March 19-June 29, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 140 pages (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 604, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, film, radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Drama; Education; Diaries; Libraries; United States; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Humanities
  - 1945 July 2-December 27, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 136 pages (Box 294, Reel M Mar 4, Frame 744)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe to assess various interests in humanities. He surveys humanities education in the Baltic States. A report on Norway is included.
    United States; Sweden; Norway; Diaries; Netherlands; Motion pictures; Humanities; Film; England; Belgium; Denmark
  - 1946 January 2-May 9, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance.
    Diaries; United States; Humanities
  - 1946 June 3-September 27, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 153 pages (Box 295, Reel M Mar 4, Frame 882)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama film, radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Diaries; United States; Motion pictures; Libraries; Humanities; Film
  - 1946 October 1-December 30, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 216 pages (Box 295, Reel M Mar 5, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to France to surveys the country's humanities interests. A report on the Unesco General Conference held in Paris is included.
    Libraries; Linguistics; Motion pictures; Museums; Film; Folklore; France; Humanities; Education; Drama; Diaries; United States
  - 1947 January 2-September 30, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 366 pages (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 217, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe and library restoration is detailed.
    United States; Museums; Motion pictures; Sweden; Norway; Film; France; Humanities; Diaries; Libraries; Education; England
  - 1947 October 1-December 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 170 pages (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 583, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio, libraries and museum assistance and research and education grants in the humanities. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe and Mexico. Marshall assesses Mexico for Rockefeller Foundation assistance in international book supply and attends the Unesco general conference.
    Norway; Museums; Belgium; Denmark; Motion pictures; Libraries; Mexico; Film; France; Education; Humanities; Language and languages; History; Diaries; Holland (Netherlands: Province)
  - 1948 January 2-May 5, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 185 pages (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 753, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies and drama. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. The Unesco Pilot Project in Fundamental Education is detailed.
    Motion pictures; Libraries; Diaries; Humanities; History; United States; Puerto Rico; Haiti; Film; Education
  - 1948 May 6-August 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 161 pages (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 938, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies and drama. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Ballet; Diaries; Puerto Rico; Radio; Drama; Humanities; Theater; United States
  - 1948 September 1-December 29, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 224 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The contents include Conference on Current Work in Language Teaching, a Pilot Project in Fundamental Education in Haiti and Marshall travels to the Middle East from 10 November- 17 December 1948 to represent the Rockefeller Foundation at the Third General Conference of Unesco.
    Cultural history; Turkey; Broadcasting; United States; Lebanon; Language and languages; Diaries; Middle East; Libraries; Film; Education; Japan; Humanities; Syria; Motion pictures
  - 1949 January 3-April 2, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 205 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 225, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. The diary details Marshall's attendance at the Committee on Near Eastern Studies of the ACLS in Washington D.C. and at the Advisory Committee on the Japanese-Korean Broadcasting Project. He travels to Haiti for the Unesco Pilot Project in Fundamental Education and includes a report of his impressions on Puerto Rico from a 28 February- 3 March 1949 trip.
    Libraries; Motion pictures; Humanities; Language and languages; Haiti; History; Drama; Film; Theater; Museums; Puerto Rico; Cultural history; United States; Diaries
  - 1949 April 4-August 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 177 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 430, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. The diary details Marshall's attendance at the Southern Humanities conference at the University of North Carolina; the Meeting of the Committee on the Japanese and Korean Broadcasting Project; the Meeting of the American Association of University Presses; Conference on Comparative History; Seminar on Educational Radio at the University of Illinois; and the Conference on World Understanding Through the Arts.
    Microfilms; Libraries; Humanities; History; Film; Education; Broadcasting; Diaries; United States; Radio; Philosophy and religion; Museums; Motion pictures
  - 1949 September 1-December 30, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 248 pages (Box 297, Reel M Mar 6, Frame 607)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program's focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. Marshall attends the Unesco General Conference and gives his impressions of the conference and assesses future relations between the Rockefeller Foundation and Unesco. He also attends the Rocky Mountain Radio Council in Denver, Colorado; the National Conference on Human Rights; and the Conference of the Committee on Education Reconstruction of the UN National Commission for Unesco. Marshall details a study of the Wisconsin region and surveys general education in the humanities program at the University of Syracuse.
    Diaries; United States; Radio; Humanities; Human rights; France; Broadcasting
  - 1950 January 3-April 14, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 155 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 855, Box 297)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program is reorganizing its grant programs into "Language, Logic and Symbolism" representing general interest grants in communication, and "Intercultural Understanding" promotes research and interpretative work aimed at making cultures more understandable. Marshall visits Canada, Princeton University and attends the National Theater Conference.
    Slavic studies; Radio; Language and languages; Diaries; Humanities; Dramatists; Drama; Canada; Broadcasting; Theater; United States
  - Trip to Near East, 1950 April 17-May 17; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 105 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1,010, Box 297)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The contents include Marshall's trip to the Near East to assess if humanities projects in the Middle East could be related to Rockefeller Foundation interests.
    Culture and Intellectual History; Syria; Iraq; Libraries; Humanities; Iran; Education; Egypt; Diaries
  - 1950 May 18-August 11, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 186 pages (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1,115, Box 297)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The contents include notes on the Fifth General Conference of Unesco, Conference on Arab Outlook held at Harvard University and the Harvard Summer Institute.
    France; Humanities; Drama; Dramatists; Diaries; Libraries; Italy; Theater; Playwriting
  - 1950 September 19-December 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 220 pages (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 1, Box 297)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. Marshall discusses humanities grants with hopeful applicants and receives progress reports on current projects. He surveys the University of California at Los Angeles Department of Theatre Arts. He attends various conferences including the New School for Social Research's Conference on Economic Development Abroad; Young Playwrights Committee Meeting; Meeting of the Writers in the IIE Young Artist Exchange Program; and the Regional Conference of the National Commission of Unesco in Havana, Cuba.
    Theater; Motion pictures; United States; Film; Education; Libraries; Diaries; Humanities; Cuba; Dramatists; Drama
  - Index, 1951-1958; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 33 pages (Box 298, Reel M Mar 7, Frame 221)
    33 pages
  - 1951 January 2-February 6, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 80 pages (Box 298, Reel M Mar 7, Frame 254)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program is reorganizing its grant programs into "Language, Logic and Symbolism" representing general interest grants in communication, and "Intercultural Understanding" promotes research and interpretative work aimed at making cultures more understandable, and "Humane values" such as creative writing, literature, history, philosophy and work in the other arts. Marshall attends a meeting of ACLS.
    Motion pictures; Theaters; Diaries; United States; Drama; Film; Humanities
  - Trip to Near East, 1951 February 16-March 18; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 134 pages (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 334, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He takes a trip to the Near East to assess and survey Rockefeller Foundation Humanities program interests. The diary includes "Tentative list of Participants for Conference on Contemporary Studies of the Arab World."
    Iraq; Language and languages; Lebanon; Middle East; Syria; Education; Egypt; Humanities; Cultural history; Diaries
  - 1951 March 18-June 13, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 280 pages (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 468, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He takes a trip to the Near East to assess and survey Rockefeller Foundation Humanities program interests. The diary includes general impression reports on Egypt, Lebanon, Iraq and Turkey. Marshall also attends the U.S. National Commission for Unesco in Washington D.C.
    Diaries; Humanities; Iraq; Lebanon; Middle East; Education; England; Syria; Turkey
  - Index, 1951 June 15-October 15; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 747, Box 298)
    Index; 9 pages.
    Middle East -- Study and teaching; Diaries; England; France; Humanities; Middle East; Education
  - 1951 July 17-October 15, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
    Diaries; Education; Humanities